http://www.physikinstrumente.com/en/about-pi/legal-information/privacy-policy/#c67298

Close navigation0PI WorldwideLanguageDEEN
Menu
ProductsOEMApplicationsTechnologyNews & EventsAbout PICareersPI BlogPI StoreBack
Products
Show pageNew ProductsProduct FinderCustomized ProductsNanopositioning Piezo Flexure StagesMiniature StagesLinear StagesLinear ActuatorsRotation StagesXY StagesHexapodsEngineered Subsystems for AutomationFast Multi-Channel Photonics AlignmentMotion Control SoftwareControllers & DriversPiezoelectric Transducers & ActuatorsAir Bearings & StagesSensors, Components & AccessoriesVacuumBack
Applications
Show pageHexapods Support Industrial RobotsScientific InstrumentationSemiconductor TechnologyMicroscopySilicon PhotonicsMedical TechnologyMaterials ResearchMechanical EngineeringAutomationBeamline InstrumentationAdditive ManufacturingActive AlignmentBack
Technology
Show pagePiezo TechnologyPiezoelectric DrivesElectromagnetic DrivesParallel KinematicsSensor TechnologiesControllers & SoftwareGuiding Systems & Force TransmissionVacuumGlossaryBack
News & Events
Show pageNews & PressTrade Fairs & EventsPI Youtube ChannelPI LinkedIn ProfileBack
About PI
Show pageTechnology CenterFractal Manufacturing Structure at PIMetrologyManufacturing in Cleanrooms at PIHeavy Load HallCertified QualityThe PI GroupAbout PI miCosAbout PI InnovationAbout ACS Motion ControlPI WorldwideHow to Get to PI!Back
Careers
Show pageCareers at PIJobs at PIKarlsruheLederhoseEschbachBack
Nanopositioning Piezo Flexure Stages
Show pageMulti-Axis Piezo Flexure StagesPIFOC® Objective & PInano® Sample Scanners for MicroscopyLinear Piezo Flexure StagesXY Piezo Flexure StagesXYZ Piezo Flexure ScannersPiezo Flexure Tilting MirrorsBack
Miniature Stages
Show pageMiniature Linear StagesMiniature Rotation StagesMiniature HexapodsBack
Linear Stages
Show pageStages with Magnetic Direct-Drive Linear MotorStages with Stepper, DC & Brushless DC (BLDC) MotorsVertical Stages with Stepper, DC & Brushless DC (BLDC) MotorsMiniature Linear StagesBack
Linear Actuators
Show pagePiezoMike for Long-Term StabilityLinear Actuators with Stepper & DC Servo MotorsPIMag® VC Voice Coil Actuators with High Dynamics & Force Control OptionPiezoMove Lever ActuatorsNanopositioning Piezo ActuatorsPiezoWalk® Actuators with High Force & StabilityPIRest Active Piezo ShimsBack
Rotation Stages
Show pageV-610 Compact PIMag® Rotation StageV-611 Rotation StageBack
Hexapods
Show pageH-900KSCO Fast 6-Axis HexapodM-850KWAH Weather-Resistant Hexapod for AstronomyM-850KLAH Large-Aperture High-Load HexapodP-911KNMV UHV-Compatible Miniature Piezo HexapodBack
Motion Control Software
Show pageConceptsUser Programs and Their FunctionsSoftware Tools for HexapodsProgrammingThird Party SupportSoftware Products for Special ApplicationsBack
Controllers & Drivers
Show pageNanopositioning Piezo ControllersPiezo Drivers for Open-Loop Operation of Piezo ActuatorsMotion Controllers & Drivers for Linear, Torque, Stepper & DC Servo MotorsControllers & Drivers for PiezomotorsController Systems for Multiple Axes & Mixed Drive TypesHexapod Motion ControllersACS Motion ControlBack
Piezoelectric Transducers & Actuators
Show pageDiscs, Rods and CylindersPlates and BlocksRingsTubesSpheres and HemispheresBending ElementsTube ActuatorsPICMA® Piezo Linear ActuatorsPICMA® Piezo Bender ActuatorsPICA Piezoelectric Stack ActuatorsPICA Shear ActuatorsDuraAct Patch TransducersPicoactuator® Piezoelectric CrystalBack
Scientific Instrumentation
Show pageHexapod Systems for ALMADouble-Crystal MonochromatorMaterials Research in High VacuumActive Vibration Isolation with Piezo ActuatorsDrive Technology for the ELTBack
Microscopy
Show pageConfocal MicroscopyPositioning Solutions for Total Internal Reflection Fluorescence Microscopy (TIRFM)High-Speed MicroscopyAtomic Force MicroscopyWhite Light InterferometryFlamingo Lightsheet Fluorescence MicroscopyIsoView Light Sheet MicroscopeBack
Silicon Photonics
Show pagePhotonics PackagingOptical Fiber AlignmentBack
Medical Technology
Show pageEndoscopySurgical Robots for OphthalmologyMagnetic Resonance ImagingOptical Coherence TomographyPipettingPrecision DosingMicropumpsImage StabilizationAdaptive Diaphragm PositioningPositioning Solutions for Whole Genome SequencingBack
Materials Research
Show pageParallel Kinematics for Materials ResearchLaser Beam ControlBack
Mechanical Engineering
Show pageElectrical Discharge MachiningHexapods in Mechanical EngineeringBack
Automation
Show pageSmarter Motion PositioningHexapods in MicroproductionHexapods for Quality AssuranceMagnetic Direct DrivesMotion Simulation with HexapodsFlexibility in Dimensional MeasuringMotion Compensation with HexapodsFast Piezo Ultrasonic Drives Advance TechnologyLaser Material ProcessingHexapods for Optical MetrologyBack
Beamline Instrumentation
Show pageTomography EquipmentSynchrotron Spectroscopy in VacuumBeam PreparationSample Positioning for TomographyMicroscopyAccelerator TechnologyBack
Piezo Technology
Show pageFundamentals of Piezo TechnologyProperties of Piezo ActuatorsPiezoceramic MaterialsManufacturing TechnologyPICMA® TechnologyIntegrated Piezo ActuatorsDuraAct Patch Transducer TechnologyPIRest ActuatorsBack
Piezoelectric Drives
Show pagePiezo ActuatorsPiezoWalk® Walking DrivesPILine® Ultrasonic PiezomotorsPiezo Inertia DrivesPiezoMike Linear ActuatorsComparison: Piezo Motors & Drive TechnologiesBack
Electromagnetic Drives
Show pageRotating Electric MotorsMagnetic Direct DrivesPIMag® 6-D Magnetic LevitationHybrid ConceptBack
Parallel Kinematics
Show pageParallel KinematicsMulti-Axis PositionersHexapod as Motion SimulatorBack
Sensor Technologies
Show pageCapacitive SensorsIncremental SensorsPIOne Optical Nanometrology EncoderComparison: Position Sensor TechnologiesBack
Controllers & Software
Show pageDigital & Analog InterfacesEtherCAT Connectivity of PI ProductsControl of Piezo ActuatorsDigital Motion ControllersSoftwareActive AlignmentBack
Guiding Systems & Force Transmission
Show pageClassical Guiding SystemsFlexure Guiding SystemsMagnetic BearingsPIglide Air Bearing TechnologyBack
Trade Fairs & Events
Show pageVirtual Trade Show StandsBack
Karlsruhe
Show pageOur BenefitsExperienced & Young ProfessionalsStudentsTrainees & Dual Curriculum StudentsBack
Lederhose
Show pageOur BenefitsExperienced & Young ProfessionalsStudentsTrainees & Dual Curriculum StudentsBack
Eschbach
Show pageOur BenefitsExperienced & Young ProfessionalsStudentsTrainees & Student InternshipsPhysik Instrumente (PI) GmbH & Co. KG
Auf der Roemerstrasse 1
76228 Karlsruhe
Germany
Phone
+49 721 4846-0
Fax
+49 721 4846-1019
Email
info@pi.ws
Web
www.physikinstrumente.com
Cookie Settings
International ContactLegal InformationPrivacy Policy GeneralTerms and Conditions of SaleConditions for BorrowingGeneral Software License AgreementBackQuote list
Contact us
Go to quote list
Back
Login
Loading ...HomeAbout PILegal InformationPrivacy PolicyWe are very pleased that you are interested in our company. Data protection is of particular importance. As a matter of principle, the use of the Internet pages is possible without the disclosure of any personal data. However, if a data subject wishes to make use of special services of our company via our website, it may be necessary to process personal data. If processing personal data is necessary and there is no legal basis for such processing, we generally obtain the consent of the data subject.
Processing of personal data, such as the name, address, email address or telephone number of a data subject, is always carried out in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation and in accordance with the country-specific data protection regulations applicable to our company. In accordance with this data protection declaration, our company would like to inform the public about the type, scope, and purpose of the personal data collected, used, and processed by us. Furthermore, this data protection declaration informs the data subject of his/her rights.
As the entity responsible for processing, our company has implemented numerous technical and organizational measures to ensure that the personal data processed via this website is protected as completely as possible. Nevertheless, breaches of security are possible with Internet-based data transmission and absolute protection cannot be guaranteed. For this reason, it is possible for each person to transmit personal data to us by alternative means, for example by telephone.
1. Definition of Terms
Our data protection declaration is based on the terms used by the European legislator when the General Data Protection Regulation (EU GDPR) was issued. Our data protection declaration should be easy to read and understand for the public and for our customers and business partners. To ensure this, we would like to explain the terms used in advance.We use the following terms in this data protection declaration:a) Personal Data Personal data is all information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (hereinafter referred to as "data subject"). Identifiable is a natural person who can be identified directly or indirectly, in particular by assignment to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or one or more special characteristics that express the physical, physiological, genetic, psychological, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.b) Data Subject The data subject is any identified or identifiable natural person whose personal data is processed by the person responsible.c) Processing Processing means any process or series of processes carried out with or without the aid of automated procedures in relation to personal data, such as the collection, organization, sorting, storage, adaptation or alteration, reading, retrieval, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or any other form of provision, comparison or linking, restriction, erasure or destruction.d) Restrictions on Processing Restrictions on processing refers to marking stored personal data with the objective of restricting future processing.e) Pseudonymization Pseudonymization is the processing of personal data in such a way that the personal data cannot be assigned to a specific data subject without the use of additional information, provided that this additional information is kept separately and is subject to technical and organizational measures that ensure that the personal data is not assigned to an identified or identifiable natural person.f) Entity or Person Responsible for Processing The entity or person responsible for processing is the natural or legal person, public authority, institution or other body that, either alone or together with others, decides on the purposes and means of processing personal data. Where the purposes and means of such processing are laid down by Union law or by the law of the Member States, the person responsible or the specific criteria for his appointment may be laid down in accordance with Union law or the law of the Member States.g) Processor The processor is a natural or legal person, authority, institution or other body that processes personal data on behalf of the person responsible.h) Recipient The recipient is a natural or legal person, authority, institution or other body to which personal data is disclosed, irrespective of whether it is a third party or not. However, authorities which may receive personal data under Union law or the law of the Member States within the scope of a particular investigation mandate shall not be regarded as recipients.i) Third Party A third party is a natural or legal person, authority, institution or other body other than the data subject, the person responsible, the data processor and the persons authorized to process the personal data under the direct responsibility of the entity responsible or the data processor.j) Consent Consent shall mean any informed and unequivocal expression of will be given voluntarily by the data subject for the specific case in the form of a declaration or other clear affirmative act by which the data subject indicates his or her consent to the processing of personal data concerning him or her.
2. Name and Address of the Entity Responsible for Processing
The entity responsible within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation, other data protection laws in force in the Member States of the European Union and other provisions of a data protection nature is:Physik Instrumente (PI) GmbH & Co. KG Auf der Roemerstrasse 1 76228 Karlsruhe Germany Phone: +49 721 4846-0 Email: info@pi.ws Website: www.physikinstrumente.com
3. Name and Address of the Data Protection Officer
The data protection officer responsible for processing is:DIOMIKO UG Sascha Dionisius Raiffeisenstraße 7 74193 Schwaigern-Massenbach Germany Phone: +49 7138 8135574 Mobile: +49 151 50590736 Email: sd@diomiko.comAny data subject can contact our data protection officer directly at any time with any questions or suggestions regarding data protection.
4. Cookies
Our web pages use cookies. Cookies are text files which are stored on a computer system by an Internet browser.Numerous websites and servers use cookies. Many cookies contain a so-called cookie ID. A cookie ID is a unique identifier of the cookie. It consists of a string of characters that assign Internet pages and servers to the specific Internet browser where the cookie was stored. This allows the the Internet pages and servers to distinguish the individual browser of the data subject from other Internet browsers that contain other cookies. A specific Internet browser can be recognized and identified by its unique cookie ID.The use of cookies allows us to provide users of this website with more user-friendly services that would not be possible without cookies.Cookies help us to optimize the information and offers on our website for the user. As already mentioned, cookies allow us to recognize the users of our website. The purpose of this recognition is to make it easier for users to use our website. For example, the user of a website that uses cookies does not have to re-enter his access data each time he visits the website because this is taken over by the website and the cookie stored on the user's computer system. Another example is the shopping basket cookie in the online shop. The online shop uses the cookie to remember the items that a customer has placed in the virtual shopping basket.The data subject can prevent cookies being set by our website at any time by setting the Internet browser used and therefore permanently object to the setting of cookies. Furthermore, cookies that have already been set can be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This possible with all common Internet browsers. If the data subject deactivates setting of cookies in the Internet browser, not all functions on our Internet site may be used to the full.
5. Collection of General Data and Information
Our website collects general data and information each time a person or an automated system visits our website. This general data and information is stored in so-called log files on the server. We may record the types and versions of browsers used, the operating system used by the accessing system, the website from that a system accesses our website (so-called referrer), the subwebsites that are accessed via an accessing system on our website, the date and time of access to the website, an Internet protocol address (IP address), the Internet service provider of the accessing system and other similar data and information that serve to avert danger in the event of attacks on our information technology systems.We do not draw any conclusions on the data subject when using this general data and information. Instead, this information is required to deliver the contents of our website correctly, to optimize the contents of our website as well as the advertising, to ensure the permanent functionality of our information technology systems and the technology of our website and to provide law enforcement authorities with the information necessary for criminal prosecution in the event of a cyber-attack. Therefore, this anonymously collected data and information is evaluated by us statistically and also with the objective of increasing data protection and data security in our company and ultimately to ensure an optimum level of protection for the personal data processed by us. The anonymous data in the server log files is stored separately from all personal data provided by a data subject.
6. Contact via the Website
Because of legal regulations, the website contains information that allows fast electronic contact with our company and direct communication with us, which also includes a general address for so-called electronic mail (email address). If a data subject contacts the person responsible for processing the inquiry via email or a contact form, the personal data transmitted by the data subject will be automatically stored and used. If necessary, this data is provided to the PI subsidiaries or retailers for further processing. The personal data is not passed on to any other third party.
7. Routine Deletion and Blocking of Personal Data
The entity responsible for processing shall process and store the personal data of the data subject only for the time necessary to achieve the data retention purpose or to the extent provided for by the European legislator or other legislator in laws or regulations that the entity is subject to.If the reason for storage ceases to apply or if a storage period prescribed by the European legislator or any other applicable legislator expires, the personal data is routinely blocked or deleted in accordance with the statutory provisions.
8. Rights of the Data Subject
a) Right to Confirmation Every data subject shall have the right as granted by the European legislator of directives and regulations to require the entity to confirm whether personal data concerning him/her is being processed. If a data subject wishes to exercise this right of confirmation, he or she may contact our data protection officer or another employee of the entity responsible for processing at any time.b) Right of the Data Subject to Information Any person affected by processing of personal data shall have the right as as granted by the European legislator of directives and regulations to obtain information on any personal data stored relating to him/her from the entity responsible for processing and demand a copy of that information. Furthermore, the European regulator requires that the data subject is entitled to the following information:reasons for processingthe personal data categories that are processedthe recipients or categories of recipients to whom the personal data have been or are still being disclosed, in particular recipients in third countries or international organizationsif possible, the duration planned for storing the personal data and if this is not possible, the criteria for determining that durationthe right of rectification or deletion of personal data concerning him or restrict processing by the entity responsible for processing or the right to oppose such processinga right of appeal to a supervisory authorityif the personal data is not collected from the data subject: All available information on the origin of the datathe existence of automated decision-making, including profiling in accordance with Article 22 paragraphs 1 and 4 GDPR and, at least in these cases, meaningful information on the logic involved and the scope and intended effects of such processing for the data subjectFurthermore, the data subject has a right of access to information to determine whether personal data have been transferred to a third country or to an international organization. If this is the case, the data subject also has the right to obtain information on the appropriate guarantees in conjunction with the transfer. If a data subject wishes to exercise this right to information, he or she may contact our data protection officer or another employee of the entity responsible for processing at any time.c) Right to Correction Any data subject to the processing of personal data shall have the right as granted by the European legislator of directives and regulations to request immediate correction of inaccurate personal data concerning him/her. Furthermore, with respect to the purpose of processing, the data subject has the right to request the completion of incomplete personal data, including a supplementary declaration. If a data subject wishes to exercise this right to correction, he or she may contact our data protection officer or another employee of the entity responsible for processing at any time.d) Right to Cancellation (Right to be Forgotten) Any data subject affected by processing of personal data shall have the right as granted by the European legislator of directives and regulations to require the person responsible to request immediate deletion of his/her personal data, provided that one of the following reasons applies and insofar the processing is deemed not necessary:The personal data was collected or otherwise processed for purposes that are no longer necessary.The data subject withdraws his/her consent on the basis for processing, and where there is no other legal basis for the processing pursuant to Article 6 paragraph letter a GDPR or Article 9 paragraph 2 letter a GDPR.The data subject opposes processing under Article 21 paragraph 1 GDPR and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for processing or the data subject opposes processing under Article 21 paragraph 2 GDPR.The personal data was processed unlawfully.The deletion of personal data is necessary to fulfil a legal obligation under Union law or the law of the Member States that the person responsible is subject to.The personal data was collected relating to information society services offered in accordance with Art. 8 para. 1 GDPR.If one of the above-mentioned reasons applies and the data subject wishes to have personal data stored with us deleted, he or she may contact our data protection officer or another employee of the entity responsible for processing at any time. Our data protection officer will ensure that the request for deletion is complied with without delay.e) Right to Restrict ProcessingAny data subject affected by processing of personal data shall have the right as granted by the European legislator of directives and regulations to require the person responsible to restrict processing if one of the following conditions is met:The accuracy of the personal data is disputed by the data subject for a period that allows the person responsible to verify the accuracy of the personal data.Processing is unlawful, the data subject refuses to delete the personal data and instead, requests that the use of the personal data be restricted.The person responsible no longer needs the personal data for the purposes of the processing, but the data subject needs them to assert, exercise or defend legal claims.The data subject objects to processing pursuant to Art. 21 para. 1 GDPR and it has not yet been determined whether the legitimate reasons of the data subject outweigh those of the person responsible.If one of the above conditions is met and a person affected wishes to request restriction of personal data stored by our company, he or she can contact our data protection officer at any time. The data protection officer will arrange for processing to be restricted.f) Right to Data Transferability Any data subject affected by processing of personal data shall have the right as granted by the European legislator to receive personal data relating to him/her from a person responsible in a structured, current and machine-readable format. They shall also have the right to transmit such data to another person responsible without obstruction by the person responsible to whom the personal data was made available, provided that processing is based on the consent provided for in Article 6 paragraph 1 letter a GDPR or Article 9 paragraph 2 letter a GDPR or on a contract in accordance with Article 6 paragraph 1 letter b GDPR and that processing is carried out using automated procedures, unless processing is necessary for the performance of a task in the public interest or in the exercise of public authority conferred on the person responsible. Furthermore, in exercising his right to data transferability pursuant to Article 20 paragraph 1 GDPR, the data subject has the right to demand that personal data be transferred directly by a person responsible to another person responsible, provided this is technically feasible and provided that the rights and freedoms of other persons are not affected. The person affected may contact the data protection officer or another employee at any time to assert the right to data transferability.g) Right of Objection Any person affected by processing of personal data shall have the right as granted by the European legislator for reasons related to his/her particular situation to object at any time to processing of personal data concerning them under Article 6 paragraph 1 letter e or f GDPR. This also applies to profiling based on these provisions. We will not continue to process personal data in the event of an objection, unless we can prove compelling grounds for processing that outweigh the interests, rights and freedoms of the data subject or the processing serves to assert, exercise or defend legal claims. If we process personal data to carry out direct advertising, the data subject has the right to object to the processing of personal for the purpose of such advertising at any time. This also applies to profiling insofar as it is connected with such direct advertising. If the data subject objects to our company processing for direct marketing purposes, we will discontinue processing personal data for these purposes. Furthermore, the data subject has the right to object to processing of his/her personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or for statistical purposes in accordance with Article 89 paragraph 1 GDPR related to his/her particular situation, unless such processing is necessary for the performance of a task in the public interest. The data subject may contact the data protection officer directly to exercise the right of objection. Notwithstanding Directive 2002/58/EC, the data subject shall also be free to exercise his right of opposition with respect to the use of information society services by means of automated procedures that use technical specifications.h) Automated Decisions in Individual Cases Including Profiling Any person affected by processing of personal data shall have the right as granted by the European legislator not to be subject to a decision based exclusively on automated processing, including profiling, which has legal effect against him or significantly affects him in a similar way, provided that the decision is not necessary for the conclusion or performance of a contract between the data subject and the person responsible, or is admissible under Union or Member State law that the person responsible is subject to, and that such law contains appropriate measures to safeguard the rights, freedoms and legitimate interests of the data subject or is taken with the data subject's express consent. Where a decision is necessary for the conclusion or performance of a contract between the data subject and the data controller or is taken with the express consent of the data subject, we shall take appropriate measures to safeguard the rights, freedoms and legitimate interests of the data subject, including at least the right to demand intervention of a person by the person responsible, to state his own position and to challenge the decision. If the person concerned wishes to assert rights with respect to automated decisions, he or she can contact our data protection officer at any time.i) Right to Revoke Consent under Data Protection Law Any person affected by processing of personal data has the right as granted by the European legislator to withdraw his or her consent to the processing of personal data at any time. If the data subject wishes to exercise his/her right to withdraw his/her consent, he/she may contact our data protection officer or another employee of the entity responsible for processing at any time.
9. Data Protection for Applications and During the Application Process
The entity responsible for processing collects and processes the personal data of applicants for the purpose of processing the application. Processing can also be done electronically. This is particularly the case if an applicant sends corresponding application documents to the entity responsible for processing electronically, for example, by email or via a form on the website. If the entity responsible for processing concludes an employment contract with an applicant, the data transmitted will be stored for the purpose of processing the employment relationship in compliance with the statutory provisions. If the entity responsible for processing does not conclude an employment contract with the applicant, the application documents shall be deleted automatically three months after notification of the decision of refusal, provided that no other legitimate interests of the entity responsible for processing contradict deletion. Other legitimate interest in this sense is, for example, a burden of proof in proceedings under the General Equal Opportunity Act (German Allgemeinen Gleichbehandlungsgesetz - AGG).
10. Legal Basis for Processing
Art. 6 I letter a GDPR serves as a legal basis for processing where we obtain consent for a specific processing purpose. If processing of personal data is necessary for fulfilling a contract where the the data subject is a contracting party, as is the case for example, when processing is necessary for the delivery of goods or the provision of other services or return services, processing is based on Art. 6 I letter b GDPR. The same applies to necessary for precontractual purposes, for example, for enquiries on our products or services. If our company is subject to a legal obligation that requires processing of personal data, for example to fulfil tax obligations, the processing is based on Art. 6 I letter c GDPR. In rare cases, it may be necessary to process personal data in order to protect the vital interests of the data subject or any other natural person. This would be the case for example, when a visitor were injured on our company premises and his name, age, health insurance data or other vital information had to be passed on to a doctor, a hospital or other third parties. Processing would then be based on Art. 6 I letter d GDPR. Ultimately, processing could be based on Art. 6 I letter f GDPR. Processing not covered by any of the aforementioned legal provisions are based on this legal framework if processing is necessary to safeguard a legitimate interest of our company or a third party, provided the interests, fundamental rights and freedom of the data subject do not prevail. Such processing is permitted in particular when it has been mentioned specifically by the European legislator. In this respect, the European legislator took the view that a legitimate interest could be assumed if the person affected is a customer of the person responsible (recital 47, second sentence, GDPR).
11. Justified Interests in Processing Pursued by Entity Responsible or a Third Party
If processing of personal data is based on Article 6 I letter f GDPR, it is in our legitimate interest to conduct our business for the well-being of all our employees and our shareholders.
12. Duration, for which Personal Data is Stored
Personal data is stored only as long as needed for the purpose of processing your enquiry. If no further statutory obligation for storing personal data is necessary, it will be deleted after processing.
13. Legal or Contractual Regulations for the Provision of Personal Data; Necessity for Conclusion of the Contract; Obligation of the Data Subject to Provide Personal Data; Possible Consequences of Failure to Provide
We inform you that provision of personal data is partly required by law (e.g., tax regulations) or may also result from contractual regulations (e.g., information on the contractual partner). In some cases, it may be necessary for a contract to be concluded if a data subject provides us with personal data that we must subsequently process. For example, the person affected is obliged to provide us with personal data if our company enters into a contract with him/her. Failure to provide personal data would mean that the contract with the data subject could not be concluded. Before personal data is provided by the data subject, the data subject must contact our data protection officer. Our data protection officer will inform the data subject on a case-by-case basis whether provision of personal data is required by law or contract or required for the conclusion of the contract, whether there is an obligation to provide the personal data and what consequences failure to provide the personal data would have.
14. Using Social Plug-ins
FacebookIt may be possible that social plug-ins ("plug-ins") of the social network facebook.com operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook") are used on the PI Internet pages. This relates in particular to the "Like" button of Facebook.When you visit one of our Internet pages that includes such a plug-in, your browser will establish a direct connection to the Facebook servers. Facebook will transmit the content of the plug-in directly to your browser, which will include it into the Internet page. By the integration of the plug-ins, Facebook will receive the information that you have accessed the Internet page concerned. If you are logged in into your Facebook account while visiting the website, Facebook can assign the visit to your Facebook account. When you interact with the plug-ins, e.g. by pressing the "Like" button" or writing a comment, the corresponding information will be transmitted directly to Facebook by your browser and stored there.For the purpose and the scope of the data collection and the further processing and use of the data by Facebook as well as your rights and the setting options for protecting your privacy, please refer to the >> data protection information of Facebook.If you do not want that Facebook assigns the visit on our website to your Facebook account, you have to log out of Facebook before visiting our website. LinkedInWe continue to use the LinkedIn "Share function" on our website. The provider is LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. If you are logged into LinkedIn and click the "Share" button (plug-in), you will be redirected to your user account in a separate browser window and can add a comment and then share the electronic publication deposited on our website. The plug-in is used to connect your browser directly to the LinkedIn server. This means that LinkedIn receives information on your IP address and your visit to our website. It will also be possible for LinkedIn to associate your visit to our website with you and your user account. We point out that we are not given any information on the content of the personal data transmitted or its use by LinkedIn. Please read LinkedIn's data protection policy for further information: https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy. XINGWe also use XING's "Share" function on our website. The provider is XING AG, Dammtorstraße 29-32, 20354 Hamburg, Germany. If you are logged into XING and you click the "Share" button (plug-in), you will be redirected to your user account in a separate browser window and can add a comment and then share the electronic publication deposited on our website. The plug-in is used to connect your browser directly to the XING server. This means that XING receives information on your IP address and your visit to our website. We point out that we are not given any information on the content of the personal data transmitted or its use by XING. Please read XING's data protection policy for further information: https://www.xing.com/app/share?op=data_protection. TwitterWe have integrated plug-ins on our website from Twitter Inc. You can recognize the Twitter plug-ins (tweet button) by the Twitter logo on our site. An overview of the tweet buttons is here (https://about.twitter.com/resources/buttons). When you go to one of our web pages, the plug-in connects your browser directly to the Twitter server. This means that Twitter receives information on your IP address and your visit to our website. If you click the "tweet button" while you are logged into your Twitter account, you will be able to link the contents of our site to your Twitter profile. This means that Twitter can associate the visit to our website with your user account. As provider, we point out that we are not given any information on the content of the personal data transmitted or its use by Twitter. If you do not want Twitter to associate your visit to our website, please log out of your Twitter account. Further information on Twitter's data privacy policy can be found here (https://twitter.com/privacy).
15. Privacy Policy on the Use and Application of YouTube
The entity responsible for processing has integrated components of YouTube into this website. YouTube is an Internet video portal that allows video publishers to post video clips and other users to view, rate and comment on them free of charge. YouTube allows the publication of all types of videos, which is the reason why film and television programs, music videos, trailers or videos produced by users themselves can be called up via the Internet portal.YouTube is operated by YouTube, LLC, 901 Cherry Ave, San Bruno, CA 94066, USA. YouTube, LLC is a subsidiary of Google Inc, 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, USA.Each time and page of this website is accessed that is operated by the entity responsible for processing and where YouTube component (YouTube video) has been integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the person affected is automatically prompted by the respective YouTube component to download a representation of the corresponding YouTube component. More information on YouTube can be found at https://www.youtube.com/yt/about/de. In the course of this technical procedure, YouTube and Google are informed which specific subpage of our website is visited by the person concerned. If the person affected is logged on to YouTube at the same time, YouTube recognizes which specific subpage of our website the person concerned visits by calling up a subpage that contains a YouTube video. This information is collected by YouTube and Google and assigned to the respective YouTube account of the person affected.YouTube and Google receive information via the YouTube component that the person affected has visited our website whenever the person affected is logged on to YouTube at the same time as accessing our website; this happens irrespective of whether the person affected clicks on a YouTube video or not. If transmission of this information to YouTube and Google is not desired by the person affected, they can prevent transmission by logging out of their YouTube account before calling up our website.The data protection regulations published by YouTube, which can be accessed at https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy/, provide information about the collection, processing, and use of personal data by YouTube and Google.
16. Analysing Services
This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysing service of Google Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses cookies that permit an analysis of how you have used the website. The information concerning your use of this website (including your IP address) created by the cookie is transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. But if the IP anonymization is activated on this website, the IP address will be truncated before it is transmitted within the member states of the European Union or other states that are contracting parties of the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. Google will use this information in order to evaluate your use of the website, to prepare reports about the website activities for the website operators and to provide further services connected to the use of the website and the Internet. Google might also transmit this information to a third party as far as this is legally required or if third parties process these data on behalf of Google.In no case shall Google establish a connection between your IP address with other data stored by Google.Most browsers accept cookies automatically. You can prevent this by modifying the settings of your browser. But we explicitly point out that you may then be no longer able to use all functions of the PI website to the full extent.By using this website, you consent to the processing of the data collected about you by Google in the way and for the purpose described above.Another possibility to prevent the transmission of data to Google Analytics: >> Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-ons.You can deactivate the function of having your data recorded by Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie will be set that prevents your data from being recorded when visiting this website: >> Deactivate Google Analytics.This website uses Hotjar in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices (in particular device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy by clicking on >> this link.You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this >> opt-out link.This website uses Leadfeeder, a website visitor tracking software from the finnish company Liidio Oy, Mikonkatu 17 C, 00100 Helsinki; team@leadfeeder.com; +358504303422. This service connects data from Google Analytics with lists of IP addresses from recognised companies. In this way, we are able to connect website sessions and website visitor behaviour with a company contact. We use this to generate leads. As we anonymize all IP addresses before transfering them to Google Analytics, there is no possibility to connect the recorded data to a specific person. You can prevent the transmission of data to Leadfeeder by using one of the options to deactivate Google Analytics mentioned above. Please see Leadfeeder’s privacy policy by clicking on >> this link.This website uses ClickDimensions, a website tracking service operated by ClickDimensions LLC, 5901 Peachtree Dunwoody Road, NE suite B500 Atlanta, GA 30328 United States. This software connects anonymous data from website visits with lists of IP addresses of known companies. In this way, website visits and user behaviour on the website can be associated with companies. ClickDimensions is certified for compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Agreement and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Agreement. ClickDimensions' current privacy policy can be found >> here.OK
